mcmworldwide.com 2018-05-04

# Privacy Policy

This website is provided and managed by MCM Products USA, Inc. (hereafter referred to as “MCM”, “we” and “us”).

MCM recognizes the importance of protecting the privacy of personal and financial information. MCM provides this privacy policy (“Privacy Policy”) to describe how we use, maintain, protect, disclose and process certain information that we obtain through the web site at www.mcmworldwide.com (“Site”), in e-mail, text and other electronic messages between you and the Site and when you interact with our advertising and applications on third-party Sites and services, if those applications or advertising include links to this Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy does not apply to any data that we collect offline or through any other means, including on any other Site operated by MCM or any third party including our affiliates and subsidiaries. This Privacy Policy only applies to the Site and not to any third party (including our affiliates and subsidiaries), including through any application or content (including advertising) that may link to or be accessible from or on the Site.

Please read this policy carefully to understand our policies and practices regarding your information and how we will treat it. If you do not agree with our policies and practices, your choice is not to use the Site. By accessing or using the Site, you agree to this Privacy Policy. This policy may change from time to time. Your continued use of the Site after we make changes is deemed to be acceptance of those changes, so please check the policy periodically for updates.

### TYPES OF DATA MCM COLLECTS AND PURPOSES

MCM collects certain individually identifiable data (that you actively submit through the Site (“personal data”) as well as other non-individually identifiable information that we collect through cookies, flash cookies, web beacons and other tracking technologies (“data”). Additionally, MCM collects some personal data from our customers who submit a customer information card at one of our stores,

You may purchase products, sign up for a newsletter, complete an online survey form, participate in promotions, or otherwise actively send us personal data on the Site. The personal data and data may be provided by filling in forms on our Site. We may also ask you for information when you enter a contest or promotion sponsored by us, and when you report a problem with our Site. We may collect data from records and copies of your correspondence including e-mail addresses, if you contact us, responses to surveys that we might ask you to complete for research purposes and details of transactions you carry out through our Site and of the fulfillment of your orders.

Such personal data may include your name, email address(es), billing address(es), delivery address(es), telephone number(s), credit card information, shopping patterns, and product interests. We use personal data primarily for the purpose for which you originally provided it (i.e., to sell and deliver products, to provide the requested newsletter, or the like), and for purposes of improving our products and services, market research, and customer profiling. We may use personal data to transmit direct marketing communications to you by email. You can opt-out of receiving such communications at any time by responding to the opt-out instructions within the communication.

We may also receive similar non-personally identifiable data from third parties. We use this data to provide better service to Site visitors, customize the Site based on your preferences, compile and analyze statistics and trends, to otherwise administer and improve the Site for your use, and to personalize offers.

Our Site is not intended for children under 13 years of age. No one under age 13 may provide any personal information to or on the Site. We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under 13. If you are under 13, do not use or provide any information on this Site or on or through any of its features/register on the Site, make any purchases through the Site, use any of the interactive or public comment features of this Site or provide any information about yourself to us, including your name, address, telephone number, e-mail address or any screen name or user name you may use. If we learn we have collected or received personal information from a child under 13 without verification of parental consent, we will delete that information. If you believe we might have any information from or about a child under 13, please contact us at contact.us@mcmworldwide.com. 

### DATA DISCLOSURE AND SHARING

MCM may share and receive personal data within the MCM affiliated group of companies, so that MCM may inform you of other products that may be of interest to you, improve your shopping experience, and improve our Site design. We may also disclose personal data to our franchisees for customer relationship management (ensure the same customer’s benefits worldwide), profiling and marketing purposes. You may opt-out of our sharing your personal data with such affiliates and franchisees by contacting us as described below.

We contract with selected third parties that provide services on our behalf to maintain our Site, provide our client communications, and provide other services. The personal data that we obtain through this Site may be accessed by these third parties, solely on MCM’s behalf, but we generally do not authorize these service providers to make any other use of your personal data. We may also disclose personal data to financial institutions or other third parties in connection with performing payment transactions. We do not otherwise disclose your personal data to third parties, unless required by law, necessary in connection with a legal claim or proceeding, or when otherwise necessary to protect the rights or interests of MCM or third parties. If MCM is acquired by another entity or is merged or consolidated or subject to any other corporate transaction, such as divestiture or reorganization, personal data may be made available to the prospective or actual acquiring entity. However, we will require such entity by contract to protect the personal data in a manner that is consistent with this Privacy Policy.

We may also disclose your personal data to comply with any court order, law or legal process, including to respond to any government or regulatory request.; to enforce or apply our terms of use or terms of sale and other agreements, including for billing and collection purposes and if we believe disclosure is necessary or appropriate to protect the rights, property, or safety of MCM our customers or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organizations for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction.

### ACCESS OF PRIVACY POLICY & MODIFICATIONS

By accessing and using the Site (including registering on the Site, purchasing items through our Site, or participating in promotions, social media and other communications), or by submitting a customer information card at a MCM store, you consent to our collection, use and disclosure of your information as described in this Privacy Policy. We will seek your consent as required by law before using personal data for any purpose beyond the scope of your original consent. You may withdraw your consent at any time, subject to legal and contractual restrictions and reasonable notice. Please note, however, that withdrawing consent may affect our ability to serve you and maintain our relationship. If you provide us or our agents with personal data of another individual, you represent that you have all necessary authority and/or have obtained all necessary consents from such person to enable us to collect, use and disclose such personal data for the purposes set forth in this Privacy Policy.

MCM reserves the right occasionally to make changes to our Privacy Policy or practices. We will post the updated policy on our Site, and thus we encourage you to review this page from time to time, particularly each time you use the Site. We will only use your personal data in accordance with the Privacy Policy in place at the time you provided your information, or as otherwise required or permitted by law, unless you have provided consent for us to do so otherwise.

If you are registered with us and would like to delete your registration and personal details from our database, please click on this unsubscribe link.

Please keep your personal data, accurate, current, and complete by regularly updating your personal account or by contacting us as specified below. You may ask for access to review, update or correct any information that we hold about you or determine how we collected the information, how we are using it, and to whom we have disclosed it. Your request for access must be in writing, and should be sent to our Privacy Officer (as defined below). In certain circumstances we may be unable to provide access to some or all of the information that we hold about you. If we are unable or not permitted by law to provide you with access, we will provide you with an explanation.

### DATA SECURITY

We have implemented measures appropriate to the sensitivity of your personal data designed to secure your personal data from accidental loss and from unauthorized access, use, alteration and disclosure.

But the safety and security of your information also depends on you. Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password for access to certain parts of our Site, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask you not to share your password with anyone. We urge you to be careful about giving out information in public areas of the Site like message boards. The information you share in public areas may be viewed by any user of the Site.

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your personal data transmitted to our Site. Any transmission of personal data is at your own risk. We are not responsible for circumvention of any privacy settings or security measures contained on the Site and your continued use of the Site and the provision of any personal data constitutes your acknowledgment and assumption of this risk.

### EFFECTIVE DATE AND AMENDMENTS

This Privacy Policy is effective as of February 9, 2015. We may amend this Privacy Policy from time to time at our discretion. Please check back periodically, and especially before you provide any data to us. We will only use your personal data in accordance with the Privacy Policy in place at the time you provided your information, or as otherwise required or permitted by law, unless you have provided consent for us to do so otherwise.

### COOKIES

When you visit the Site, we passively collect data through the use of cookies on your computer and Internet connection, such as the IP address of your computer and/or Internet service provider, the date and time you access the Site, the Internet address of websites from which you link to our Site, the computer technology you are using and your movements and preferences on our Site. We may also use such cookies to collect information in connection with future visits to the Site (such as to remember your username and password), to recognize you as a previous visitor, and to track your activity on the Site. You may set your browser to notify you when a cookie is sent or to refuse cookies altogether, but certain features of the Site might not work without cookies.

We reserve the right to use other technologies such as Internet tags, web beacons, and navigational data collection tools. We use such data primarily in order to: administer, protect, and improve our Site and our systems; better understand the preferences of our Site visitors; identify server problems; compile aggregated statistics about Site usage; help personalize your experience on our Site; advertise on other sites across the Internet; and personalize offers. We may combine data gathered through cookies and other tracking technologies with personal data, although when we do, we treat all such data as personal data for purposes of this Privacy Policy.

This site also uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. (“Google”). Google Analytics uses cookies to help us analyze your use of the Site, compiling reports on Site activity and providing other services relating to Site activity and Internet usage. MCM does not tie the data to any personally-identifiable information. Use of this information helps us better understand what users are seeking and helps us identify potential navigation issues. By using the Site, you consent to the processing of data about you by Google in the manner and for the purposes set out above.

### HOW MCM PROTECTS PERSONAL INFORMATION

MCM will take all precautionary measures to protect the personal data that is shared on our website. MCM [and hired third parties related to transaction and fulfillment only] store information internally in controlled, secure environments. MCM occasionally hires other companies to provide limited services on our behalf, including packaging, mailing and delivering purchases, sending postal mail and processing event registrations. MCM will only provide those companies the information they need to deliver the service, and they are prohibited from using that information for any other purpose.

If MCM requests general demographic information, this information is limited to reporting purposes only; users remain anonymous. Phone numbers, e-mail addresses, and postal addresses are never shared for demographic reports with outside entities. 

### HOW TO UPDATE YOUR PERSONAL DATA

You can help MCM maintain the accuracy of your personal data by updating the setting in My Account where you may change your name, billing & shipping address books, title, birthday, phone number, e-mail address, view your order history, or your content preferences.

If at any time you wish to update your information or preferences, or you prefer to stop receiving communication from MCM, feel free to update your preferences in My Account. For technical concerns and troubleshooting your personal data, please contact our customer service at contact.us@mcmworldwide.com at any time. 

### LINKS

Our website contains links to other websites. MCM assumes no responsibility for the content or the privacy policies and practices of such websites.

MCM encourages you to read the privacy statements of these linked sites; their privacy practices may differ from ours.

### CONTACT US

Please contact our privacy officer (the “Privacy Officer”) as the address set out below with any comments, concerns or suggestions you might have regarding the information practices described in this Privacy Policy. We will investigate any concern and seek to resolve it within a reasonable time. Our Privacy Officer can be reached at:

Email: contact.us@mcmworldwide.com.

Attention: Privacy Officer
